[Music]
[音乐]
this is nick with logosbynic.com and in
我是logosbynic.com的尼克
this lesson we'll be going over how you
这一课我们将复习一下你是如何
can create multi-page documents using
可以使用以下工具创建多页文档
inkscape now in order to follow along
Inkscape Now，以便跟随
with this lesson you'll need to update
学习本课程后，您需要更新
to version 1.2 which was just released
到刚刚发布的1.2版
yesterday because this is a new feature
昨天因为这是一项新功能
to inkscape if you remember a couple of
去Inkscape如果你还记得几个
years ago i made a tutorial
几年前我做了一个教程
demonstrating how to design pdf reports
演示如何设计pdf报表
and ebooks and various types of
电子书和各种类型的
multi-page documents but because
多页文档，但因为
inkscape didn't have the ability to do
Inkscape没有能力做到
this at the time we had to save each
这是在我们不得不拯救每个人的时候
page as an individual pdf and then merge
页面作为单独的pdf，然后合并
them together using a third-party
使用第三方将它们组合在一起
application
应用程序
but thanks to version 1.2 those days are
但多亏了1.2版，这些日子是
over so let's get started here and
结束了，让我们从这里开始
demonstrate how this works so when you
演示此功能的工作原理，当您
open up inkscape version 1.2 this should
打开Inkscape 1.2版，这应该
be your view when you first open a new
当您第一次打开一个新的
document this white square right here or
在这里记录下这个白色方块，或者
rectangle rather represents your page
矩形代表您的页面
now if you notice down here at the
现在，如果你注意到下面的
bottom of the tools menu you'll see you
在工具菜单的底部，您将看到
have a new tool here called the create
我这里有一个名为Create的新工具
and edit document pages tool if you
和编辑文档页面工具，如果您
click on that it'll activate nodes on
点击它将激活上的节点
your page right here and you can take
你的页面就在这里，你可以
these nodes and use them to scale them
这些节点并使用它们来扩展它们
and change the size of your document and
并更改文档的大小，然后
you could even move your document around
您甚至可以四处移动您的文档
the workspace like this if you need to
如果您需要这样的工作空间
do that
做那件事吧
now what you can also do with this tool
现在，您还可以使用此工具执行以下操作
is you can click and drag like this to
你可以像这样点击并拖动
create another page like that and now
创建另一个这样的页面，现在就创建
you have two different pages here
这里有两个不同的页面
okay now if you want to create an exact
好的，现在如果您想创建一个精确的
copy of a page you already have what you
页面的副本你已经有了你想要的东西
can do is you can click on one of those
你可以点击其中的一个
pages and you come up here to the tools
佩奇和你来到这里的工具
menu bar at the top of the screen and
屏幕顶部的菜单栏和
click on this little icon right here
点击这里的这个小图标
that says create a new page and when you
这就是说创建一个新页面，当您
click on that it's going to create a new
点击它将创建一个新的
page in the same dimensions that the
页面的维度与
current page that you have selected is
您选择的当前页面是
so this new page is the same size as
因此，这个新页面的大小与
this page over here
这一页在这里
now if you look over here through this
现在，如果你通过这个看这里
drop down we have all of these different
下拉我们有所有这些不同的
pre-made templates that you can choose
您可以选择的预制模板
from if you want to change the size of
如果您想要更改的大小
your page to something specific say for
你的页面上有一些特定的内容
example if you're designing a us letter
例如，如果您正在设计一封美国信函
8.5 by 11 inches you can change it to
8.5 x 11英寸，您可以将其更改为
that right there and there you go now
就在那里，就在那里，你现在就去
you have 8.5 by 11 inch document and
您有8.5 x 11英寸的文档，并且
then again you could change this using
然后，您可以使用以下命令更改此设置
these nodes at any time just as you
您可以随时使用这些节点
would with the original page
将与原始页面
okay so looking up through these uh menu
好的，查一下这些呃菜单
items right here let's go over what each
就在这里，让我们来看看每个项目
of these things do now if you notice
如果你注意到这些事情，现在就去做
over here as i click on these different
在这里，我点击这些不同的
pages you'll see up here they are
你会在上面看到的页面是
ordered one through three this is page
订购一到三，这是页面
one of three
三个中的一个
this is page two of three and this is
这是第三页的第二页，这是
page three of three this represents the
第三页(共三页)这表示
order of the pages so if i were to save
页面顺序，所以如果我要保存
this as a pdf document this would be the
这是一份pdf文档，这将是
first page this would be the second page
第一页这将是第二页
and this would be the third page if i
这将是第三页，如果我
want to change their order at any point
我想随时更改他们的顺序
all i have to do is select one of them
我所要做的就是从中选择一个
and then on either side of the order
然后在订单的两边
right here we have this one that says
就在这里，我们有一个上面写着
move page backwards
向后移动页面
and now that will be page two of three
现在这将是第三页中的第二页
even though nothing visibly changes on
即使没有什么明显的变化
the canvas if i were to save this
如果我把这个保存下来，画布
document this would be page one
文档这将是第一页
this would be page two and then this
这将是第二页，然后是这个
would be page three so let me go ahead
会在第三页，所以让我继续
and undo that
然后撤销这一切
so now this is one this is two and this
现在这是一，这是二，这是
is three and then up here we have names
是三个，然后在这上面我们有名字
you can name each page if you want this
如果你想要这个，你可以给每个页面命名
is really just for personal reference
真的只是供个人参考
this isn't going to change the name of
这不会改变
your document or anything this is just
你的文件或其他什么东西这只是
for example if you want to change this
例如，如果您要更改此设置
to
至
um i don't know like something like
呃，我不知道是不是像
brochure contents
小册子目录
there you go
好了，给你
and then over here you could write in
然后在这里，你可以写下
um
恩
business card
名片
just in case you know naming your pages
以防你知道给你的页面命名
comes in handy in some way so that's
在某种程度上很方便，所以这是
what that does and if you want to delete
它的作用是什么？如果您要删除
any of your pages what you could do is
你的任何页面你都能做的是
you can select on it like that click on
你可以像点击一样选择它
it with the tool and you could either
它与工具和您可以
press delete on your keyboard
按键盘上的Delete键
or you can click on this button over
或者您也可以在上面点击此按钮
here that says delete the selected page
此处显示的是删除所选页面
okay so let me go ahead and undo that
好的，那么让我继续解开它
let me show you what these other tools
让我向您展示这些其他工具
in here do what i'm going to do is i'm
在这里我要做的就是
going to grab the stars tool and create
要抓起星星工具并创建
a star right on top of this page right
一颗星就在这一页的正上方
here
这里
now if i go back to the pages tool if
现在如果我返回到页面工具，如果
you notice i have this option right here
你注意到我这里有一个选项
that says move overlapping objects as
也就是说，将重叠对象移动为
the page is moved this means that if i
页面被移动了，这意味着如果我
move the page the object will move with
移动对象将随其一起移动的页面
it so if i move this page you'll notice
所以，如果我移动这一页，你会注意到
the object is fixed in place it's not
物体固定在适当的位置，而不是
moving anywhere
搬到任何地方
that's because i have that setting
那是因为我有这样的设置
turned off if i turn that setting on now
如果我现在打开该设置，则关闭
when i move a page the contents of the
当我移动页面时，
page will be moved along with it like
页面将与其一起移动，就像
that as you can see there
正如你在那里看到的那样
okay so that's how that works and then
好的，这就是工作原理，然后
finally over here we have fit the page
最后，我们在这里找到了合适的页面
to the current selection or the drawing
添加到当前选定内容或图形
so if i have an object selected let me
因此，如果我选择了一个对象，让我
grab my selection tool
抓起我的选择工具
if i have an object selected like that
如果我像这样选择了一个对象
i can come back over here to the create
我可以回到这里来创造
and edit document pages and i can click
和编辑文档页面，我可以点击
on this button right here that says fit
在这里的这个按钮上写着适合
the pages to the current selection of
将页面添加到当前选定的
the drawing if i click on that you see
如果我点击这张图，你会看到
what happens there the page is now fit
那里发生了什么？页面现在适合了
to the size of that document right there
到那个文件的大小
or that object right there so that's how
或者就是那个物体，所以这就是为什么
that works
这很管用
so let me give you a working
所以让我给你一个工作机会
demonstration of how you can save a
演示如何节省
multi-page document now so let me take
现在是多页文档，所以让我来
this and get rid of this i'm going to
这个和摆脱这个我要去
grab the text tool i'm just going to
抓住文本工具，我正要去
this is just for an example here you
这只是你的一个例子
don't have to follow along with what i'm
不需要跟随我的脚步
doing i'm just going to put some numbers
我只是要把一些数字放在
on the page
在页面上
like this i'm gonna put this over here
像这样，我要把这个放在这里
just so you can visualize how this works
这样您就可以直观地看到它是如何工作的
this is page one this is gonna be page
这是第一页，这将是第一页
two and this is gonna be page three and
第二页，这将是第三页
what i'm gonna do now is in order to
我现在要做的是为了
save this as a multi-page document i'm
将此文档另存为多页文档
gonna go to file and i'm gonna go to
我要去归档，我要去
save as and i want to choose pdf down
另存为，我想选择pdf down
here
这里
and i'll click save
然后我将单击保存
leave all of the defaults as they are
保留所有默认设置不变
click ok and now what i'm going to do is
点击OK，现在我要做的是
i'm going to go and open up that pdf
我要去把那个pdf打开
document and show you how it works
记录并向您展示其工作原理
okay so as you can see here i've opened
好的，正如你所看到的，我已经打开了
up my multi-page pdf document that i've
打开我的多页pdf文档
created thanks to inkscape version 1.2
使用Inkscape 1.2版创建
and as you can see everything is in its
正如你所看到的，一切都在它的
order this was page one this was page
订单这是第一页这是第一页
two and this was page three
第二页，这是第三页
so that is how you can create multi-page
这就是创建多页的方法
documents using inkscape if you found
使用Inkscape的文档(如果找到
this lesson useful then consider
这一课很有用，然后考虑
checking out my inkscape master class
查看我的Inkscape大师课
it's a collection of over 60 videos
这是60多个视频的集合
where i go over all of the tools and
在那里我检查了所有的工具和
features in inkscape and i explain what
Inkscape中的功能，我将向您解释
they are and demonstrate how they work
它们是并演示了它们的工作方式
kind of like how i just did in this
就像我刚才做的那样
video we even have a private community
视频我们甚至有一个私人社区
where you can ask questions and get help
在这里您可以提出问题并获得帮助
from me anytime you want i'll have some
任何时候你想要我的，我都会有
information about that linked in the
中链接的相关信息。
description of the video down below as
下面的视频描述如下
always thanks for watching
永远感谢您的收看
[Music]
[音乐]